Today we have assembled here to celebrate the birth of Christ.
امروز اینجا جمع شده‌ایم تا تولد مسیح را جشن بگیریم.
When you think of His birth one knows that He was born in a very humble place
وقتی به تولد او فکر می‌کنید، انسان می‌بیند که او در محلی بسیار محقر به دنیا آمد
and all His life He lived in a very humble way.
و سرتاسر زندگی‌اش را به شیوه‌ای بسیار متواضعانه سپری کرد؛
Also, as Sahaja yogis, you know that He was the incarnation of Shri Ganesha
همچنین به عنوان یک ساهاجایوگی می‌دانید که او اینکارنیشن شری گانشا بود؛
which is, in essence, is innocence and He was
که به نوعی معصومیتش بود؛ و او به خاطر
crucified due to the stupid understanding of blind people.
درک نابخردانه آدم‌های کور، به صلیب کشیده شد.
He was the eternal child and it’s so sad that
او کودکی ابدی بود و بسیار غم‌انگیز است که
when we talk about Christ and Christianity
وقتی در مورد مسیح و مسیحیت صحبت می‌کنیم،
we feel that Christianity has gone just the other way around,
احساس می‌کنیم مسیحیت درست برعکس،
on the other side of Christ.
بر خلاف مسیح گام برداشته است.
If one is construction, the another is destruction
در مسیری بر خلاف مسیح گام برداشته است. اگر یکی ساختن است، آن دیگری تخریب است؛
and if one is innocence, another is cunning.
و اگر یکی معصومیت است، آن دیگری فریبکاری است.
If you see the Christian nations, it's very surprising where we have got Christianity
اگر اقوام مسیحی را ببینید، بسیار تعجب‌آور است در جایی که
in its practice; it's very surprising that innocence has no place, no respect,
به مسیحیت عمل می‌شود، خیلی تعجب‌آور است که معصومیت، هیچ جایگاه و احترامی ندارد
chastity has no place, no respect, which was the essence of Christ,
پاکدامنی، هیچ جایگاه و احترامی ندارد، که آن ذات مسیح بود.
He was made of it.
او از آن ساخته شده بود.
It is sometimes shocking how these so-called Christian nations
گاهی این که چطور این اقوام به اصطلاح مسیحی،
have maligned Christ to that extent
تا ا‌ین حد، از مسیح بدگویی کرده‌اند
and how they have ruined so many people with their stupid ideas
و این همه آدم را با عقاید احمقانه خودشان نابود کرده‌اند، تکان‌دهنده است.
of allowing people to indulge into all kinds of filthy things.
عقایدی که به آنها اجازه افراط در هر کار کثیفی را می‌دهد.
And the second point is very important, to see how
و دومین نکته، خیلی مهم است که ببینیم چطور
He was born in a very humble abode,
او در یک محل بسیار محقر زاده شد،
He lived in a very humble way.
به شکلی بسیار فروتنانه زندگی کرد؛
He was a son of a carpenter so He lived like a carpenter,
او پسر یک نجار بود؛ برای همین مثل نجارها زندگی کرد.
but in the Western life people are so materialistic
ولی در زندگی غربی، آدم‌ها بسیار مادی‌گرا شده‌اند
and to them to live lavishly, to show off their wealth
و برای آنها زندگی اشرافی و به رخ کشیدن ثروتشان
and to plunder people, plunder countries after countries
و غارت مردم، غارت کشورها یکی پس از دیگری
for material gain is a common thing.
برای اهداف مادی، امری معمول است.
They do not feel also that it is wrong and they are quite proud of it.
فکر هم نمی‌کنند که این کار غلط است و کاملا به آن افتخار می‌کنند؛
And the third great thing about Christ was that
و سومین مطلب مهم در مورد مسیح این بود که
He wanted people to love each other and to be humble,
او از مردم خواست یکدیگر را دوست داشته باشند و فروتن باشند.
but the arrogance and the cruelty that one has seen of the Christian nations
ولی با آن تکبر و ستمگری که انسان در کشورهای مسیحی دیده است،
one cannot understand how are they anywhere near Christ.
نمی‌تواند هیچ شباهتی به مسیح را در آنها درک کند.
He has said about, "Blessed are those who are meek".
در این ارتباط او گفته: آنها که خاضعند، مورد رحمت هستند.
Where are those meek people living? Not in the western countries,
آن افراد خاضع کجا زندگی می‌کنند؟ نه در کشورهای غربی هستند،
not in the countries where Christ is worshipped, where temples are raised,
نه در کشورهایی که در آنجا مسیح ستایش می‌شود، جایی که معابد
are raised in His honor and have been worshipping the Mother for so many years.
به افتخار او بنا می‌شوند و سال‌ها است که مادر را ستایش کرده‌اند.
What a sinful thing it is to do to Christ.
چه عمل گناه‌آلودی است که در حق مسیح روا می‌دارند.
Is the greatest sin that we say that we are following Christ
بزرگ‌ترین گناه است که بگوییم پیرو مسیح هستیم
and to do all these horrible things,
و دست به تمامی این اعمال ناشایست بزنیم؛
all such people have to go to hell of the worst type, no doubt about it.
تمامی چنین افرادی باید به بدترین نوع جهنم بروند؛ شکی در آن نیست.
They may not realize but they are already getting into it,
شاید متوجه نباشند؛ ولی آنها همین الان دارند وارد جهنم می‌شوند،
they are already having this problem.
آنها همین حالا این مشکل را دارند.
They are worse than people who crucified Christ, this is every-day crucifixion.
آنها بدتر از افرادی هستند که مسیح را به صلیب کشیدند؛ این، مصلوب کردن هر روزه است.
So it's a great occasion today to celebrate
پس امروز فرصت بسیار مناسبی است
the birth of Christ, who came on this earth to help us in our resurrection,
که تولد مسیح را جشن بگیریم که بر این زمین آمد، تا به رستاخیز ما کمک کند،
to talk about the Holy Ghost.
تا درباره روح‌القدس صحبت کند.
He was bearing all the brunt of the people, everything,
او بار همه مردم را به دوش ‌کشید، همه چیز را؛
but the outcome of that life is so horrifying that sometimes I get worried
ولی نتیجه آن زندگی چنان بد است که گاهی نگران می‌شوم
that I hope they don't make something out of Me like that.
و دعا می‌کنم به من هم همان نظر را نداشته باشند.
It is such a stupid ideas people have in the west,
مردم در غرب چنان افکار احمقانه‌ای دارند
that for any sensible man he can see the way
که هر آدم عاقلی می‌تواند بفهمد
they are emotional, romantic, nonsensical. They have no respect
چطور هیجانی، احساساتی و بی‌مغز هستند. آنها هیچ احترامی برای خودشان قائل نیستند
for themselves and to follow Christ with that kind of an attitude is, I think is,
و با آن نگرش،اگر بخواهند از مسیح پیروی کنند، به نظر من
they have no business, they have no right, but it has happened.
چنین حقی ندارند، اجازه‌اش را ندارند. ولی اینچنین شده است.
Now you people are born again as Christ has said, "You are to be born again".
حالا شما مردم دوباره متولد شده‌اید؛ همان‌طور که مسیح گفت: قرار است شما دوباره متولد شوید.
You have achieved that state which Christ was talking about.
شما به مرتبه‌ای رسیده‌اید که مسیح از آن سخن گفت.
You are the special type of people. I never had such hopes I must say.
شما نوع خاصی از انسان‌ها هستید، باید بگویم تا حالا چنین امیدی نداشتم.
The first encounter was so horrible that I didn't think that many will come out of it
اولین مواجهه‌ای که داشتم چنان بد بود که فکر نمی‌کردم خیلی‌ها سربلند بیرون بیایند؛
but so many of you have come out of it
ولی خیلی از شما سربلند بیرون آمدید
and have really glorified the name of Christ, no doubt about it, and keep it up.
و به نام مسیح واقعا شکوه بخشیدید؛ شکی در آن نیست؛ و همین‌طور ادامه دهید.
I would request you now to know that you are Sahaja yogis
از همه شما حالا خواهش می‌کنم بدانید، این شمایید که ساهاجایوگی هستید
and that you are the followers of Christ.
و شمایید که پیرو مسیح هستید،
You are the Gnostics as described, you are the ones who know
شما همان عارفانی هستید که می‌گفتند، شما آنهایی هستید که می‌دانند
and that's how you have to help people to emancipate.
و همان‌طور هم شما باید به مردم کمک کنید تا رهایی یابند.
It is very surprising that I saw that the Western life,
خیلی تعجب برانگیز است که دیدم زندگی غربی،
the stupid, destructive ideas, did not kill the innocence.
عقاید احمقانه و مخرب، معصومیت را نکشت.
Like the clouds, all these affectations were there
همچون ابر، تمامی این تأثیرات وجود داشتند؛
but once the Kundalini rose the innocence started expressing itself.
ولی وقتی کندالینی بیدار شد، معصومیت به ابراز وجود خود پرداخت؛
But still, I would say that this kind of lovey-dovey stuff
ولی هنوز هم باید بگویم که می‌بایست از این قبیل عشق‌بازی‌ها، دست بر دارید.
must be given up. It is just most un-Christian
این دقیقا بدترین کار ضد مسیحی است؛
because if you see His life, it was a life of a tapasvi,
چون اگر زندگی او را ببینید، زندگی یک زاهد بود.
a man who lived in a very detached manner, in nisanga.
مردی بود که با وارستگی بسیار زندگی کرد، در نیسْهانگا.
So for Sahaja yogis who are coming from Christian life
پس ساهاجایوگی‌هایی که از یک زندگی مسیحی می‌آیند،
have to understand if they have to get rid of it, they should be like that.
باید بدانند که با رهایی از چنین چیزی، همچون او باشند.
But on the contrary, see the interest in marriages,
ولی برعکس، مثلا میزان علاقه به ازدواج،
the interest in all this kind of thing and after marriage - is a bit too much.
میزان علاقه به این چیزها و بعد از ازدواج کمی زیاد است.
It is so much in it, I mean it’s absurd, it's absurd in Sahaja Yoga.
خیلی زیاده‌روی در آن است، یعنی این کار بی‌معنی است، در ساهاجایوگا این کار بی‌معنی است.
It's one of the lifestyles, is alright, one of the part, it's not everything;
این یکی از سبک‌های زندگی است، باشد یک بخش است؛ همه چیز که نیست؛
and it covers the whole entire personality of a Christian personality.
و روی تمامی شخصیت یک انسان مسیحی را می‌گیرد.
Not with Muslims or Hindus, I've seen that. I mean, I'm married too.
نه برای مسلمانان یا هندوها، این را دیده‌ام. یعنی من هم ازدواج کرده‌ام.
But it doesn't cover My whole entire being with it. How can it?
تمام وجود من با آن پوشانده نمی‌شود. چطور بتواند؟
And that's the problem is - that once marriage system starts, anything starts,
و مشکل این است که وقتی سیستم ازدواج به راه می‌افتد، همه چیز شروع می‌شود؛
“oh it becomes so important” and I'm faced with problems all the time.
وای، این خیلی مهم می‌شود؛ و من دائم دچار مشکل هستم.
The marriage is performed then letters will be coming,
ازدواج که انجام شد، نامه‌ها سرازیر می‌شود
“this has happened to my marriage”. They must get married,
که این اتفاق برای ازدواج من پیش آمد.
nobody is such that, supposing now one is finished,
آنها باید حتما ازدواج کنند، هیچ‌کس این طور نیست که مثلا حالا این یکی نشد،
live without marriage, they cannot do it, just can't live.
بدون ازدواج زندگی کنیم. نمی‌توانند چنین کاری بکنند. نمی‌توانند زندگی کنند.
Christ never got married.
مسیح هرگز ازدواج نکرد.
They cannot have that tapasvita in them and they depend so much,
آنها نمی‌توانند چنین ریاضی را بکشند و خیلی وابسته می‌شوند؛
they'll ruin their wives, they'll ruin their husbands, they'll ruin Sahaja Yoga.
آنها زنانشان را خراب می‌کنند، شوهرانشان را خراب می‌کنند، ساهاجایوگا را خراب می‌کنند؛
They'll take them away - but it's something surprising -
آنها را برمی‌دارند می‌برند. ولی این چیز جالبی است،
the importance of Sahaja Yoga is so minimized by this Christian mind,
اهمیت ساهاجایوگا آن‌قدر با این اذهان مسیحی کم می شود،
[that?] I don't know from where these ideas have come to you.
که نمی‌دانم از کجا این افکار به ذهنشان خطور می‌کند.
It's a juxtaposition as you can call it, juxtaposition.
این به قول شما، می‌شود گفت یک سرهم‌بندی است؛ سرهم‌بندی.
There is no similarity between the life Christ must have thought
هیچ شباهتی وجود ندارد بین آن زندگی که قطعا مسیح
people would lead and the people are leading.
برای مردم تصور می‌کرده و آن زندگی که دارند می‌کنند.
So it is necessary for Sahaja yogis to have a dignity and a sense
بنایراین برای ساهاجایوگی‌ها لازم است که وقار و عقل داشته باشند
and to know that they are grounded in Sahaja Yoga
و بدانند که آنها در ساهاجایوگا ریشه‌دار شده‌اند
and marriage and all those things are just subsidiary. It's not the end of life.
و ازدواج و دیگر چیزها فرع قضیه هستند. آخرِ زندگی نیست؛
And when I see that happening I am rather surprised in Sahaja Yoga
و وقتی این اتفاقات را در ساهاجایوگا می‌بینم، تا حدی حیرت‌زده می‌شوم.
I have to marry people because I believe that one should lead a proper married life.
من ناچارم که افراد را به ازدواج هم دربیاورم، چون عقیده دارم که انسان باید زندگی متأهلی درستی داشته باشد؛
Because if you just take up a sanyasa without going through this married life,
چون اگر بخواهید به دور از چنین زندگی، ریاضت پیشه کنید،
you can be very much hypocritical.
ممکن است بسیار ریاکار شوید.
But that doesn't mean that marriage is everything.
ولی بدین معنی نیست که ازدواج همه چیز است.
It's not so important, it's just something has to happen.
ازدواج خیلی اهمیت ندارد. فقط چیزی است که باید اتفاق بیفتد.
It's not even important than any puja;
حتی به اندازه هیچ کدام از پوجاها اهمیت ندارد،
it's not even important than praying to Me;
حتی به اندازه دعا کردن به من اهمیت ندارد،
it's not even important than meditating;
حتی به اندازه مدیتیشن اهمیت ندارد،
it's not important at all than even eating your food.
حتی اصلا به اندازه غذا خوردنتان اهمیت ندارد.
The more I know you start making of it you fall into the same trap
هر چه بیشتر به خاطرش سرو صدا راه بیندازید، به همان اندازه به دامی خواهید افتاد
from where I pulled you out.
که من شما را از آن بیرون کشیده‌ام.
So as I, the other day I was telling people about what they have to do
پس مثل همان روزی که داشتم به مردم می‌گفتم
about these caste system we have in India. So in the society of Sahaja yogis,
با این سیستم طبقاتی که در هند داریم چه باید بکنند. پس در جامعه ساهاجایوگی‌ها هم
it should be only a one day affair or two day affair at the most.
باید نهایتا کار یک یا دو روز باشد.
But so much importance, husband, wives, getting married,
ولی این‌قدر اهمیت دادن؛ زن و شوهر که ازدواج کردند،
then solving their problems, I get a headache with them.
نوبت حل مشکلاتشان که می‌شود، من از دستشان سردرد می‌گیرم.
And they'll always come "my wife, you know, she's like this,
و دائم می‌گویند که: می‌دانید زنم این‌طوری است،
and wife's sister like that, and wife's this".
و خواهرزنم آن‌طوری، و فامیل‌هایش این‌طوری؛
I mean, one should be ashamed even to say that "my wife".
و آدم حتی باید شرم کند که بگوید زن من.
In India nobody says like that. I don't think anybody will say "my wife".
در هند هیچ‌کس این‌طوری نمی‌گوید. فکر کنم هیچ‌کس نمی‌گوید، زن من.
It's not done. At the most they'll say "my children's mother",
حداکثر بگویند: مادر بچه‌های من
and if you have no children you don't say anything.
و اگر هیچ بچه‌ای نداشته باشید، چیزی نمی‌گویید.
So this is the doom from which you have come out. Please try to understand.
این سرنوشت بدی است که از آن نجات پیدا کرده‌اید، سعی کنید این را بفهمید.
From hell we have come out, absolutely wrong ideas we had,
ما از جهنم نجات پیدا کرده‌ایم، عقاید کاملا اشتباهی داشتیم
from there we have come out, now be dignified, be sensible.
که از آن نجات یافته‌ایم؛ حالا با وقار باشید، عاقل باشید؛
An over-importance to such un-important thing
و اهمیت دادن بیش از حد به چیزهایی که این‌قدر بی‌اهمیت است،
will not allow you to rise very high in life.
نمی‌گذارد خیلی در زندگی بالا بروید.
But I don't say you don't marry, you must marry.
ولی نمی‌گویم ازدواج نکنید، شما باید ازدواج کنید.
Of course, if you have a Sahaja yogini who is also a good Sahaja yogini and she knows
البته اگر یک ساهاجایوگینی داشته باشید که ساهاجایوگینی خوبی هم باشد
about Sahaja Yoga and then of course you are helped much more, definitely.
و ساهاجایوگا را بشناسد، آن وقت البته به شما خیلی بیشتر کمک شده؛ مطمئنا.
You get much more power, much more understanding, much more joy
شما قدرت بسیار بیشتری پیدا می‌کنید، فهم بسیار بیشتری، لذت بسیار بیشتری؛
and it's very good but the entire relationship is so important
و این خیلی خوب است. ولی روابط خویشاوندی بر سر مسائل کوچک کوچک آن‌قدر اهمیت دارد
on small, small things, this is just beyond Me to understand.
که از درک من خارج است.
Then I see that then the girls fall in love with the man whom they marry, finished;
بعد می‌بینم دختران عاشق مردانی می‌شوند که متأهل هستند؛ تمام است.
the man is finished, the woman is finished.
کار مرد تمام است، زن هم تمام.
Today I am taking this great occasion to tell you
امروز دارم از این موقعیت بسیار بزرگ استفاده می‌کنم که بگویم
that Christ was born to Immaculata;
حضرت مسیح از معصوم متولد شد؛
and that's how I have given you your second birth
و به همان ترتیب من به شما تولد دوباره داده‌ام
and you are so pure.
و شما بسیار پاک هستید.
So all the impurities, you must see them clearly.
پس تمام ناپاکی‌ها را باید به وضوح ببینید.
I know you don't like them but they still creep from here and there.
می‌دانم شما آنها را دوست ندارید، ولی هنوز آنها از اینجا و آنجا سر بر می‌آورند.
Of course if the society you see in the west is a society which
البته در جامعه‌ای که در غرب می‌بینید، جامعه‌ای است که
of course there is no family, no wife, nothing of the kind,
البته هیچ خانواده‌ای، هیچ همسری، هیچ چیزی نیست؛
so it's just slightly better than that - but again you get stuck.
برای همین کمی بهتر از آن است. ولی شما دوباره گیر می‌افتید.
If you have to come up to this stage, you have to give up the staircase.
اگر باید که وارد صحنه شوید، می‌بایست دست از این پله‌ها بکشید.
You think that you have achieved a lot because now you have a settled family
شما فکر می کنید که دستاوردهای زیادی داشته‌اید؛ چون خانواده آرامی دارید،
and settled children and you are only worried about your own children all the time.
بچه‌های‌ آرامی دارید و فقط دائم نگران بچه‌های خودتان هستید؛
No, it's another temptation; it's [a] very big temptation.
نه؛ این وسوسه دیگری است، وسوسه خیلی بزرگی است.
So on the great occasion of the birth of Christ we have to say to ourselves
پس در این رویداد بسیار بزرگ تولد مسیح، باید به خودمان بگوییم
that we are dedicated to Sahaja Yoga,
که ما سرسپرده ساهاجایوگا هستیم.
that's the main thing, everything is subsidiary.
ساهاجایوگا موضوع اصلی است. هر چیز دیگری فرعی محسوب می‌شود.
I hope you'll understand that we are now
امیدوارم این را متوجه شوید که ما الان
on the cusp of a wave from where we are going to jump onto another wave,
در رأس موجی هستیم که قرار است از آن بر موج دیگری پرش کنیم
which will be much higher than this, but you must have the worthiness.
که بسیار بلندتر از این خواهد بود؛ ولی شما باید استحقاقش را داشته باشید.
If you are not sea-worthy you’ll be drowned,
اگر شما قابل دریا نباشید، غرق خواهید شد.
so we have to develop that worthiness - and we have Christ before us.
پس باید آن استحقاق را پیدا کنیم و ما در مقابلمان مسیح را داریم،
What a life, what a life it was.
عجب زندگی‌ای! عجب زندگی‌ای بود!
He lived like a human being in a humble way and what a life.
او مثل یک انسان، به شکلی متواضعانه زندگی کرد؛ و چه زندگی‌ای!
And how truthfully forthright He was to say everything so clearly.
و چقدر صادق و روراست بود که همه چیز را به روشنی گفت،
In the same way you'll have your strength
به همان شکل، شما هم همان قدرت خودتان را خواهید داشت،
when you will know that you are much more than a married man
وقتی که بفهمید خیلی بالاتر از یک مرد متأهل
and you are much more than your nationality.
و خیلی بالاتر از ملیت خودتان هستید.
You are a higher personality,
شما شخصیتی بالاتر هستید؛
a Sahaja yogi who is dwelling in the bliss of the Kingdom of God.
یک ساهاجایوگی هستید که در رحمت قلمرو خداوند زندگی می‌کند.
That's the bliss, not the family bliss and the children bliss, but the bliss of God.
این رحمت است؛ نه رحمت خانواده و رحمت فرزندان؛ بلکه رحمت خداوند است.
May God bless you.
رحمت خداوند شامل حال شما باشد.